readinghorizons.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy - Reading Horizons

Reading Horizons Privacy Policy

Last update: May 18, 2018

At Reading Horizons, we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Policy explains when and why we collect personal information about our visitors, how we use it, and your rights regarding this data. We may change this Policy from time to time, so please check back occasionally. 

By visiting any of our websites or online products, you are agreeing to be bound by this policy.

## Who are we? 

HEC Software Inc, doing business as Reading Horizons, is a provider of materials and software to teach reading using the Reading Horizons method. We have been in business for over 30 years and are headquartered at 1194 W Flint Meadow Drive, Kaysville, Utah 84025. Our business phone number is (800)333-0054.

What does this policy apply to? 

This Policy applies readinghorizons.com, other websites belonging to Reading Horizons, Reading Horizons’ online services and tools, and other interactions (“Properties.”) Examples of other interactions are customer service requests or conference calls. User Data specific to our software products is covered under the Reading Horizons Software Privacy Policy. 

This Policy does not apply to any third party services integrated with the Reading Horizons platform or websites.

What information do we collect? 

Reading Horizons may collect data in a number of ways:

  * Personal Data We may collect personally identifiable information, such as your full name, phone, number, and email address when you register for an account or request information or content from any of our websites. We only collect this data when you voluntarily provide it. 
  * Automatic and Technical Data We also automatically collect certain technical data that is sent to us from the computer, mobile device and/or browser through which you access our Properties. Automatic and Technical Data, includes without limitation, a unique identifier associated with your access device and/or browser (including, for example, your Internet Protocol (IP) address) characteristics about your access device and/or browser, statistics on your activities on the Properties, information about how you came to the Properties and data collected through Cookies, Pixel Tags, Local Shared Objects, Web Storage and other similar technologies. When you submit Personal Data to us, we may associate it with Automatic and Technical Data.
  * No sensitive personal data Reading Horizons does not collect sensitive personal data.

How do we use information? 

Reading Horizons uses collected data to communicate with site users and visitors, to customize content, to show ads on other websites to users and visitors, to improve our Properties, to fulfill service requests and contracts, and to give you content or information you requested. We may send you marketing materials (only if you have given your consent,) account updates, responses to your questions, product updates, and other information relevant to Reading Horizons. 

We only share Personal Data if it is required to provide a requested service or fulfill a contract. We never sell or rent your Personal Data to others. We are allowed to disclose Personal Data when we have good reason to believe that this is legally required. We will retain Personal Data we process on behalf of our customers for as long as needed to provide our services. Reading Horizons will retain this Personal Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

We may use data for internal business purposes. For instance, your Automatic and Technical Data may be used to improve the way our website works. We do not use your information for automated decision making or profiling. 

How do we protect your data? 

We may store Personal Data itself or such information may be stored by third parties to whom we have transferred it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We take what we believe to be reasonable steps to protect data from loss, misuse, unauthorized use, access, inadvertent disclosure, alteration and destruction. However, no network, server, database or Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error-free. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us electronically. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Data.

If you are located in the European Union (“EU”) or European Economic Area (“EEA”), we will not transfer information, including Personal Data, to a country outside of the EU or EEA. Otherwise, your information may be stored, process, or transferred to a country other than the one in which you live.

Data protection law in certain jurisdictions differentiates between the “collector” and “processor” of information. In general, Reading Horizons is the processor of and the collector of information. We also use third party services who act as data processors and collectors.

What rights do you have to your information? 

If you reside in certain countries, including the EEA, you have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR.) You have the right to access the information we have on you. You can do this by contacting us as [info@readinghorizons.com](mailto:info@readinghorizons.com) with the subject “Request for Personal Data.” We may ask you to verify your identity. We will fulfill your request electronically unless you specifically request a different method. 

You may request your information be updated or deleted. If at any point you want Reading Horizons to update or delete the information we have about you, you can simply send us [this form](https://www.readinghorizons.com/documents/reading%20horizons%20right%20to%20be%20forgotten%20erasure%20form.pdf) by mail or e-mail. Depending on the laws where you live, we may not be legally required to comply with your request, so we will evaluate requests on a case-by-case basis. 

You have the right to block or suppress processing of your data. You have the right to data portability and may retain and reuse your Personal Data for your own use.

Generally, no one is obligated to share either Personal Data or Automatic and Technical Data, however, in that case, Reading Horizons may be unable to provide services, to grant access to certain materials and sites, or to give you access to every feature and functionality of our Properties. 

Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or how Reading Horizons uses, stores, or protects your data, please contact us at [info@readinghorizons.com](mailto:info@readinghorizons.com), or send mail to:

Reading Horizons

1194 W Flint Meadow Dr

Kaysville, UT 84025

United States
